<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes"?><rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom"><channel><title>debugging on Jennifer Reif</title><link>https://jmhreif.com/tags/debugging/</link><description>Recent content in debugging on Jennifer Reif</description><generator>Hugo -- gohugo.io</generator><language>en-us</language><lastBuildDate>Tue, 15 Aug 2023 09:00:00 -0600</lastBuildDate><atom:link href="https://jmhreif.com/tags/debugging/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml"/><item><title>ServiceUnavailableException: Connection to the database terminated.</title><link>https://jmhreif.com/blog/sdn-service-unavailable-exception/</link><pubDate>Tue, 15 Aug 2023 09:00:00 -0600</pubDate><guid>https://jmhreif.com/blog/sdn-service-unavailable-exception/</guid><description>Photo credit I was working on a Spring Data Neo4j example application for a community user’s question, and I kept running into the error below when I defined bidirectional relationship in the domain classes.
2023-08-10T13:00:17.341-05:00 ERROR 98493 --- [nio-8080-exec-1] o.a.c.c.C.[.[.[/].[dispatcherServlet] : Servlet.service() for servlet [dispatcherServlet] in context with path [] threw exception [Request processing failed: org.springframework.dao.TransientDataAccessResourceException: Server at 408637a4.databases.neo4j.io:7687 is no longer available; Error code &amp;#39;N/A&amp;#39;] with root cause org.</description></item><item><title>Spring Data Neo4j: How to update an entity</title><link>https://jmhreif.com/blog/sdn-cypher-update-entity/</link><pubDate>Thu, 01 Jun 2023 09:00:00 -0600</pubDate><guid>https://jmhreif.com/blog/sdn-cypher-update-entity/</guid><description>Photo credit As I was incorporating Kafka to my microservices project, I ran across some trouble updating an entity in Neo4j using Spring Data Neo4j.
My data set contains books, authors, book reviews, and users. Based on a new review getting entered into the system, I want to create that review, and then update the related Book entity with an incremented review count and calculate a new average rating. The new review entity was being created with no issues, but I was struggling to get the update to the related Book entity working.</description></item><item><title>NoSuchBeanDefinitionException: No matching TransactionManager bean found for qualifier 'reactiveTransactionManager'</title><link>https://jmhreif.com/blog/no-such-bean-definition-exception/</link><pubDate>Tue, 13 Dec 2022 09:00:00 -0600</pubDate><guid>https://jmhreif.com/blog/no-such-bean-definition-exception/</guid><description>Photo credit I was working on a Spring Data Neo4j microservice application to add a write method for saving a new book review to the database, when I came across the error message below.
org.springframework.beans.factory.NoSuchBeanDefinitionException: No bean named &amp;#39;reactiveTransactionManager&amp;#39; available: No matching TransactionManager bean found for qualifier &amp;#39;reactiveTransactionManager&amp;#39; - neither qualifier match nor bean name match! The stacktrace was long and ugly, and I had come across this error before…​but I could not remember how I had solved it.</description></item></channel></rss>