<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes"?><rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom"><channel><title>neo4j on Jennifer Reif</title><link>https://jmhreif.com/tags/neo4j/</link><description>Recent content in neo4j on Jennifer Reif</description><generator>Hugo -- gohugo.io</generator><language>en-us</language><lastBuildDate>Fri, 15 Oct 2021 09:00:00 -0600</lastBuildDate><atom:link href="https://jmhreif.com/tags/neo4j/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml"/><item><title>Container Upgrade - Experiences Updating Three Databases</title><link>https://jmhreif.com/blog/docker-container-upgrade/</link><pubDate>Fri, 15 Oct 2021 09:00:00 -0600</pubDate><guid>https://jmhreif.com/blog/docker-container-upgrade/</guid><description>Photo credit *Updated Dec 16, 2021
I created a demo project a couple of years ago that included a lot of technical setup - containers, data import, queries, and such. I presented it for a conference or two, and while it was one of my favorite projects, it was a lot of preparation for the live demo.
I recently rediscovered the project, and submitted it to a couple of conferences.</description></item><item><title>Winter to Spring: Migrating from Spring Data Neo4j 5 to 6, Part 3</title><link>https://jmhreif.com/blog/migrate-sdn-part3/</link><pubDate>Wed, 22 Sep 2021 09:00:00 -0600</pubDate><guid>https://jmhreif.com/blog/migrate-sdn-part3/</guid><description>Photo credit You may have heard quite a bit of buzz around reactive programming or reactive principles in recent months or years. Some people say it is the future, while others prefer their existing monoliths. So what is all the fuss actually about? What is reactive? Is it beneficial?
As with all things in life, it depends. :) Remember, that technical decisions are often large investments of time - resources to create it and/or maintain for lengths of time.</description></item><item><title>Java 17: Explore the newly-released Java version in a graph database!</title><link>https://jmhreif.com/blog/java17-graph-explore/</link><pubDate>Tue, 14 Sep 2021 09:00:00 -0600</pubDate><guid>https://jmhreif.com/blog/java17-graph-explore/</guid><description>Photo credit I’ve recently been playing around with a JDK data set that details the historical library changes of the versions of Java, and with the release of Java 17 today (September 14!), I thought it would be a good time to explore this data set a bit more with others. I invite you to join me and to continue with additional exploration and projects!
The data set is pulled from a Marc Hofman’s Github repository for the Java Almanac that also feeds a web browser version for the javaalmanac.</description></item><item><title>Winter to Spring: Migrating from Spring Data Neo4j 5 to 6, Part 2</title><link>https://jmhreif.com/blog/migrate-sdn-part2/</link><pubDate>Thu, 09 Sep 2021 09:00:00 -0600</pubDate><guid>https://jmhreif.com/blog/migrate-sdn-part2/</guid><description>Photo credit Our previous post (Part 1) on this topic introduced us to Spring Data Neo4j and showed the architectural differences between version 5 and the latest version 6. This post begins the migration process by taking a Spring Data Neo4j 5 application with OGM and upgrades to the dependencies and syntax changes of Spring Data Neo4j 6.
Without further ado, let’s dive in!
Current application overview The code for today’s migration is a specific branch in the migration Github repository.</description></item><item><title>Winter to Spring: Migrating from Spring Data Neo4j 5 to 6, Part 1</title><link>https://jmhreif.com/blog/migrate-sdn-part1/</link><pubDate>Thu, 12 Aug 2021 09:00:00 -0600</pubDate><guid>https://jmhreif.com/blog/migrate-sdn-part1/</guid><description>Photo credit A major upgrade to Spring Data Neo4j was released at the end of last year as part of the Spring Data release train. If you were involved in Spring Data and Neo4j news before that, you may have seen hints of this coming with the SDN/RX library entering the scene in late 2019. The library brought with it a lighter footprint, as well as a more straightforward implementation of features to reduce confusion and errors (therefore also improving efficiency) in development and production.</description></item><item><title>Create a Data Marvel with Spring Data Neo4j</title><link>https://jmhreif.com/blog/create-data-marvel-sdn/</link><pubDate>Mon, 02 Aug 2021 12:00:00 -0600</pubDate><guid>https://jmhreif.com/blog/create-data-marvel-sdn/</guid><description>Photo credit I have had a couple of Github projects demonstrating bits of functionality for Spring Data Neo4j, but they had last been updated in 2020 when the new Spring Data Neo4j 6 was still a beta version known as SDN/RX. Since there have been several changes since then, I thought I would give the projects a refresh and make them current.
Project code:
SDN Marvel (imperative)
SDN(rx) Marvel (reactive)</description></item></channel></rss>