<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes"?><rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom"><channel><title>query on Jennifer Reif</title><link>https://jmhreif.com/tags/query/</link><description>Recent content in query on Jennifer Reif</description><generator>Hugo -- gohugo.io</generator><language>en-us</language><lastBuildDate>Tue, 12 Mar 2024 09:00:00 -0600</lastBuildDate><atom:link href="https://jmhreif.com/tags/query/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml"/><item><title>Cypher Sleuthing: How to Get Data Types of Properties in Neo4j</title><link>https://jmhreif.com/blog/cypher-property-data-types/</link><pubDate>Tue, 12 Mar 2024 09:00:00 -0600</pubDate><guid>https://jmhreif.com/blog/cypher-property-data-types/</guid><description>Photo credit It’s been awhile since I wrote a Cypher Sleuthing post, but I’m back with a new one! This time, I’m going to show you how to find the data types of properties in Neo4j.
I frequently want to find out the data type of a property so that I can map it in an application (in Java). I can never remember off the top of my head, and when I Google the question, the results are often outdated (here’s the answer post, but the syntax is old).</description></item><item><title>Implementing RAG: How to write a graph retrieval query in LangChain</title><link>https://jmhreif.com/blog/rag-demo-retrieval/</link><pubDate>Thu, 15 Feb 2024 09:00:00 -0600</pubDate><guid>https://jmhreif.com/blog/rag-demo-retrieval/</guid><description>Photo credit What is RAG? This term is used a lot in today’s technical landscape, but what does it actually mean? Here are a few definitions from various sources:
&amp;#34;Retrieval-Augmented Generation (RAG) is the process of optimizing the output of a large language model, so it references an authoritative knowledge base outside of its training data sources before generating a response.&amp;#34; - Amazon Web Services
&amp;#34;Retrieval-augmented generation (RAG) is a technique for enhancing the accuracy and reliability of generative AI models with facts fetched from external sources.</description></item></channel></rss>