<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes"?><rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom"><channel><title>programming on Jennifer Reif</title><link>https://jmhreif.com/tags/programming/</link><description>Recent content in programming on Jennifer Reif</description><generator>Hugo -- gohugo.io</generator><language>en-us</language><lastBuildDate>Tue, 10 Aug 2021 09:00:00 -0600</lastBuildDate><atom:link href="https://jmhreif.com/tags/programming/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml"/><item><title>Cypher Sleuthing: Dealing with Dates, Part 5</title><link>https://jmhreif.com/blog/cypher-sleuthing-dates-part5/</link><pubDate>Tue, 10 Aug 2021 09:00:00 -0600</pubDate><guid>https://jmhreif.com/blog/cypher-sleuthing-dates-part5/</guid><description>From part 1 introducing Cypher dates and formats to part 4 where we combined duration functions and temporal components to translate amounts in one unit to another unit, we have covered a lot of ground in this series! Filling in the gaps, part 2 showed us how to truncate dates for searches and use durations for adding/subtracting amounts of time, and part 3 gave us an intro to temporal components and translations within component groups.</description></item><item><title>Create a Data Marvel with Spring Data Neo4j</title><link>https://jmhreif.com/blog/create-data-marvel-sdn/</link><pubDate>Mon, 02 Aug 2021 12:00:00 -0600</pubDate><guid>https://jmhreif.com/blog/create-data-marvel-sdn/</guid><description>Photo credit I have had a couple of Github projects demonstrating bits of functionality for Spring Data Neo4j, but they had last been updated in 2020 when the new Spring Data Neo4j 6 was still a beta version known as SDN/RX. Since there have been several changes since then, I thought I would give the projects a refresh and make them current.
Project code:
SDN Marvel (imperative)</description></item><item><title>Cypher Sleuthing: Dealing with Dates, Part 4</title><link>https://jmhreif.com/blog/cypher-sleuthing-dates-part4/</link><pubDate>Tue, 27 Jul 2021 12:00:00 -0600</pubDate><guid>https://jmhreif.com/blog/cypher-sleuthing-dates-part4/</guid><description>My previous part 1, part 2, and part 3 posts on this topic introduced Cypher dates, translated formats to the Cypher-supported ISO 8601 format, calculated durations, accessed components, and translated durations to certain values.
If you read those, then this post is the next post showing how to convert durations across component categories. If you haven’t read the previous posts leading up to this one, feel free to catch up (recommend at least Part 3 as this post’s prequel) — though it isn’t required.</description></item><item><title>Cypher Sleuthing: Dealing with Dates, Part 3</title><link>https://jmhreif.com/blog/cypher-sleuthing-dates-part3/</link><pubDate>Thu, 01 Jul 2021 12:00:00 -0600</pubDate><guid>https://jmhreif.com/blog/cypher-sleuthing-dates-part3/</guid><description>My previous part 1 and part 2 posts on this topic introduced Cypher dates, translated formats to the Cypher-supported ISO 8601 format, calculated durations, and measured lengths of time. If you read those, then this post is the next step with Cypher dates on date components, component translations, and duration conversions. If you haven’t read parts 1 or 2, feel free to catch up - though this post doesn’t require the previous ones.</description></item><item><title>Cypher Sleuthing: Dealing with Dates, Part 2</title><link>https://jmhreif.com/blog/cypher-sleuthing-dates-part2/</link><pubDate>Mon, 26 Apr 2021 12:00:00 -0600</pubDate><guid>https://jmhreif.com/blog/cypher-sleuthing-dates-part2/</guid><description>My previous part 1 post on this topic introduced Cypher dates and translated a few other date formats to the Cypher-supported ISO 8601 format. If you read that, then this post is the next step with Cypher dates that covers durations and more. If you haven’t seen part 1, feel free to catch up - though this part 2 doesn’t necessarily require reading part 1. :)
We will continue a bit of the last post by showing how to truncate dates and times.</description></item><item><title>Cypher Sleuthing: Dealing with Dates, Part 1</title><link>https://jmhreif.com/blog/cypher-sleuthing-dates-part1/</link><pubDate>Fri, 09 Apr 2021 12:00:00 -0600</pubDate><guid>https://jmhreif.com/blog/cypher-sleuthing-dates-part1/</guid><description>No matter what database, programming language, or webpage you might be using, dates always seem to cause headaches. Different date formats require calculations between application date pickers in user-friendly formats and system dates in backend devices and data sources. Then, programming languages each have their own libraries and structures for dealing with dates, too.
This concept in the Neo4j ecosystem isn’t any less complex with Cypher (a graph query language) date formats, the APOC library date functions/procedures, and countless possible integration tools/APIs for data import and export.</description></item><item><title>In the Language Wars, Java Holds Its Own</title><link>https://jmhreif.com/blog/java-holds-its-own/</link><pubDate>Mon, 18 Nov 2019 12:00:00 -0600</pubDate><guid>https://jmhreif.com/blog/java-holds-its-own/</guid><description>We all pick our favorites and downplay other options (colors, cars, sports team, etc.). Programming language choice is not exempt. Whether it’s the one we are most comfortable with or the one that got us a job, we cling to that choice.
Today, we will focus on Java. There are perfectly valid complaints and praises for this language, and we will cover them. As always, these are my experiences, so others may see things differently.</description></item></channel></rss>