<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes"?><rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom"><channel><title>microservices on Jennifer Reif</title><link>https://jmhreif.com/tags/microservices/</link><description>Recent content in microservices on Jennifer Reif</description><generator>Hugo -- gohugo.io</generator><language>en-us</language><lastBuildDate>Thu, 27 Jan 2022 09:00:00 -0600</lastBuildDate><atom:link href="https://jmhreif.com/tags/microservices/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml"/><item><title>Journeys in Java, Level 2: Building an Empire of Microservices</title><link>https://jmhreif.com/blog/microservices-level2/</link><pubDate>Thu, 27 Jan 2022 09:00:00 -0600</pubDate><guid>https://jmhreif.com/blog/microservices-level2/</guid><description>Photo credit In my last blog post, we began building microservices in Java with two Spring Boot applications, passing a &amp;#34;Hello, World!&amp;#34; string from one application to the other. We focused on reduced complexity, minimum previous knowledge, and few components. Next, we can slowly add pieces that simulate microservices projects in the real world.
One way to do this is by adding a data domain. Applications often model some scenario in the real world such as maintaining office building temperatures, finding connected devices on a network, or recommending a tv show.</description></item><item><title>Journeys in Java, Level 1: Building an Empire of Microservices</title><link>https://jmhreif.com/blog/microservices-level1/</link><pubDate>Tue, 21 Dec 2021 09:00:00 -0600</pubDate><guid>https://jmhreif.com/blog/microservices-level1/</guid><description>Photo credit Microservices have been used and deployed in businesses and projects for awhile, and there is plenty of content available for architecting them into a system. For my next project, I want to dive into the world of microservices and begin building my own little virtual empire from different kinds of services to find out the complexities, best practices, power, and trouble that comes with them. I will share all my learnings along the way, as well.</description></item></channel></rss>