<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes"?><rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom"><channel><title>story on Jennifer Reif</title><link>https://jmhreif.com/tags/story/</link><description>Recent content in story on Jennifer Reif</description><generator>Hugo -- gohugo.io</generator><language>en-us</language><lastBuildDate>Thu, 18 Oct 2018 12:00:00 -0600</lastBuildDate><atom:link href="https://jmhreif.com/tags/story/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml"/><item><title>Getting Past Beginner Stage: How to Get to Intermediate</title><link>https://jmhreif.com/blog/how-to-get-to-intermediate/</link><pubDate>Thu, 18 Oct 2018 12:00:00 -0600</pubDate><guid>https://jmhreif.com/blog/how-to-get-to-intermediate/</guid><description>When you start a new technology or learn anything new, it might be easy to get started. There is often a lot of starter material, tutorials, guides, exercises, and entry-level project examples. Plus, you might even find blog posts, StackOverflow questions, and other types of materials to help you.
The on-boarding process for new technologies continues to get simpler and easier. But what happens when you understand and can tackle all the beginner-level materials?</description></item><item><title>How to Build a Career: Telling Your Story</title><link>https://jmhreif.com/blog/how-to-build-a-career/</link><pubDate>Fri, 31 Aug 2018 12:00:00 -0600</pubDate><guid>https://jmhreif.com/blog/how-to-build-a-career/</guid><description>Oftentimes, we tend to sell ourselves short when we are talking to interviewers, professionals, or other career authorities.
We don’t want to seem arrogant and inflate our capabilities, right? What if they don’t see the value of our journey that we see from our path, decisions, experiences, etc? There is a very fine balance between being humble and arrogant, and it is a tough one to achieve.
We all have different backgrounds, achievements, struggles, and experiences.</description></item></channel></rss>