<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes"?><rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom"><channel><title>programming languages on Jennifer Reif</title><link>https://jmhreif.com/tags/programming-languages/</link><description>Recent content in programming languages on Jennifer Reif</description><generator>Hugo -- gohugo.io</generator><language>en-us</language><lastBuildDate>Mon, 18 Nov 2019 12:00:00 -0600</lastBuildDate><atom:link href="https://jmhreif.com/tags/programming-languages/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml"/><item><title>In the Language Wars, Java Holds Its Own</title><link>https://jmhreif.com/blog/java-holds-its-own/</link><pubDate>Mon, 18 Nov 2019 12:00:00 -0600</pubDate><guid>https://jmhreif.com/blog/java-holds-its-own/</guid><description>We all pick our favorites and downplay other options (colors, cars, sports team, etc.). Programming language choice is not exempt. Whether it’s the one we are most comfortable with or the one that got us a job, we cling to that choice.
Today, we will focus on Java. There are perfectly valid complaints and praises for this language, and we will cover them. As always, these are my experiences, so others may see things differently.</description></item><item><title>Cypher Sleuthing: the CASE statement</title><link>https://jmhreif.com/blog/cypher-sleuthing-case-statement/</link><pubDate>Wed, 24 Jul 2019 12:00:00 -0600</pubDate><guid>https://jmhreif.com/blog/cypher-sleuthing-case-statement/</guid><description>I was recently working on one of our developer guides (the CSV import guide) and came across some Cypher I needed to fine-tune in the CASE statement on that page. I had some trouble finding the correct syntax, so I reached out to some Cypher experts to get some help.
As it turns out, I was looking at the Cypher CASE statement the wrong way and misunderstood its structure and design.</description></item><item><title>Cypher Sleuthing: the EAGER operator</title><link>https://jmhreif.com/blog/cypher-sleuthing-eager-operator/</link><pubDate>Wed, 24 Jul 2019 12:00:00 -0600</pubDate><guid>https://jmhreif.com/blog/cypher-sleuthing-eager-operator/</guid><description>Why is it that some query syntax seems to run faster than another when there is very little difference between the statements? Sometimes, queries will invoke what is called the eager operator in order to maintain consistent operations and avoid conflicting data changes.
It still leaves the question, though, of what does this eager operation do differently and why would it be important enough to specifically avoid in certain situations?</description></item></channel></rss>